training.gov.au 2015-06-07

# training.gov.au - Privacy policy

Privacy Policy for the training.gov.au website (the website)

© Commonwealth of Australia 2013

All personal information collected by the Department of Education and Training (the Department) is protected by the _Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act)_. A copy of the Privacy Act can be obtained on [ComLaw](http://www.comlaw.gov.au/) and further information on the _Privacy Act_ can be found on the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner’s website](http://www.oaic.gov.au/privacy-portal/index.html) _._

Information we collect and how we use it

The Commonwealth of Australia, acting through the Department co-ordinates the training.gov.au website.

The Department helps the Australian Government achieve its overall objective of quality educational, employment and training outcomes for all Australians through:

  * efficient national program management;

  * effective working relationships with state and territory governments, education departments, non-government education, science and training authorities, Indigenous education service providers, industry, community groups and other stakeholders;

  * auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services; and

  * policy advice and other support to the Minister.

Generally, the Department collects personal information in order to properly and efficiently carry out its functions (including those listed above), and only uses personal information for the purposes for which it was given to the Department and for directly related purposes (unless otherwise required by or authorised under law).

In addition to this general Privacy Policy, where more detailed information is needed to explain our privacy practices, we publish separate privacy notices to describe how we will handle personal information that we collect.

Communication - emails and Electronic Forms

The training.gov.au servers may record your email address if you send us a message online. Your email address will not be added to a mailing list, unless you have provided it to us in order to subscribe to one of the training.gov.au subscription services.

Where you choose to send us a completed electronic form (for example, when you register as a user on the training.gov.au website) that includes your personal details, we collect personally identifiable information, such as name and email address.

The information collected by email or electronic forms will be used only for the purpose for which you provided it, and we will not disclose it unless one of the circumstances described below under the heading “Information Sharing” has been satisfied.

###  Log information (Browsing)

When you access training.gov.au online services, the training.gov.au servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your server address, your top level domain name (for example, .com, .gov, .au, .uk, etc.), the date and time of visit to the site, the pages accessed and documents viewed, the previous sites visited, and the browser type, browser language, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

###  Cookies

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. It is information that your web browser sends back to our web site server whenever you visit it again. We use cookies to ‘remember’ your browser between page visits. In this situation, if you log into the training.gov.au website the cookie will store your user credentials.

###  Access and alteration of records containing personal information

If you provide personal information in relation to the training.gov.au online services, the Department will allow you access to your personal information and we will correct your personal information if it is inaccurate (subject to restrictions on such access/alteration of records under the applicable provisions of any law of the Commonwealth).

The _Freedom of Information Act 1982_ also provides you with an opportunity to request access to documents in the possession of the Department. For more information visit the Department’s Freedom of Information page at http://innovation.gov.au/AboutUs/InformationPublicationScheme/Pages/FreedomofInformation.aspx

###  Information sharing

The Department only discloses personal information to third parties in the following circumstances:

  * Where you are reasonably likely to have been aware, or made aware by way of a privacy notice, that your personal information is usually passed to the relevant parties;

  * Where you have consented;

  * Where we believe on reasonable grounds that the disclosure is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to your life or health or that of another person;

  * Where the disclosure is required or authorised by or under law; or

  * Where the disclosure is reasonably necessary for the enforcement of the criminal law or of a law imposing a pecuniary penalty, or for the protection of the public revenue.

###  Information security

The Department takes all reasonable steps:

  * to protect the personal information that we hold against loss, against unauthorised access, use, modification or disclosure and against other misuse; and

  * to ensure that, where we have given personal information to a contractor (that carries out service for the Department), that contractor complies with the Information Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act.

###  Data integrity

The Department takes reasonable steps to make sure that the personal information we collect and store is accurate, relevant, up-to-date, complete and not misleading.

###  Enforcement

If you have any questions/complaints about privacy, confidentiality or access to your personal information, please contact the Department’s Privacy Contact Officer by writing to:

Privacy Contact Officer

Legal Services Branch

Department of Education and Training

GPO Box 9880 Canberra ACT 2601

Alternatively, you may email your correspondence to [privacy@education.gov.au](mailto:privacy@education.gov.au)

You may also contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner directly, via telephone on 1300 363 992 or email to: [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au). Visit [http://www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/) for more information.

###  Changes to this policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time.

###  Further Information

The Department is required to submit a Personal Information Digest (PID) to the Australian Information Commissioner each year, which outlines, amongst other things, the sorts of records of personal information that the Department holds. The Department’s PIDs are available from the former [Office of the Australian Privacy Commissioner’s website’](http://www.privacy.gov.au/government/digests).

**Last updated: November 2013**
